Pedro Alburqueque

Hollywood, FL 33020 | (754) 736 - 0330 | pralburco@gmail.com | LinkedIn Profile | Portfolio

Summary

Highly motivated accounting professional with over 7 years of experience with focus in payroll processing, accounts payable, and data analysis/reporting. Possesses advanced skills in MS Office with great emphasis in Excel including pivot tables, vlookup, advanced functions/formulas, macros, and platforms such as Data Plus, Paycom, and SMS. Demonstrates exceptional soft skills, including empathy, curiosity, positivity, confidentiality, and customer service.

Skills

- Accounting: Payroll Processing, Journal Entries, Accounts Payable
- **Technical:** Advanced level of MS Excel (pivot tables, vlookup, functions/formulas, macros, etc.)
- Platforms: Data Plus, Paycom, SMS, Aloha Enterprise POS
- **Soft Skills:** Empathy, curiosity, positivity, confidentiality, customer service, analytical, and organizational

Experience

Staff Accountant | Trump International Beach Resort | December 2020 - Present

- Implements, maintains, and reviews payroll processing in a timely and accurate manner
- Reviews payroll calculations for weighted overtime, salaries, garnishments, and deductions
- Reviews Payroll updates, Personnel Action Forms, to process payments for new hires, terminations, final payments, salary increases, market adjustments, and others
- Reviews all departments' timecards for missing punches, PTO requests, and manager approvals
- Runs and submits weekly Approaching OT reports to assist in managing excessive overtime
- Prepares weekly Labor and Productivity report which analyses current labor against budget
- Processes bi-weekly payroll including calculations for service charges, commissions, and tips
- Reconciles gratuity payments with liability accounts with accuracy and efficiency
- Prepares and uploads biweekly payroll journal entries including earnings, benefit deductions, employee and employer taxes
- Calculates and prepares the monthly payroll accruals journal entry as well as reversal
- Maintains accurate Cash records for house banks and hotel's petty cash vault
- Administers petty cash disbursements and supplies Front Desk and F&B with adequate funds
- Prepares daily bank deposits and balances reports and monitor the resort's ATM fund levels
- Produces the hotel's association shared credit based on payroll for specific staff
- Assists in the ongoing transition to a new accounting system which includes accounts conversions to match the new chart of accounts

Accounting Generalist | Trump International Beach Resort | December 2014 - December 2020

- Entered large volumes of invoices and credit memos and reconciled against PO's daily
- Processed weekly check runs and off-cycle/manual checks with great attention to detail
- Established and maintained communication with vendors and stayed current with invoicing
- Ensured invoices and payroll off-cycle checks were paid on time following company policies
- Resolved vendor inquiries and payment discrepancies on a timely basis
- Routed incoming invoices to the corresponding department's head for approvals
- Reconciled vendor statement of accounts and researched discrepancies
- Processed the AP month-end tasks and closing

Food Court Manager | Ark Restaurants | January 2009 - December 2014

- Assisted the General Manager and Executive chef with scheduling and purchase orders
- Delegated tasks, enforced company's SOP's and policies, and provided guidance and training
- Provided resolution to guests' complaints
- Processed daily documentation for closing and communicated incidents with fellow managers
- Trained new team members in our POS platform, cash handling procedures and other SOP's
- Used revenue forecast reports to maintained adequate staff daily

Education

Full Stack Web Development Certificate | University of Miami | March 2021

References

Provided upon request